Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 8: Boxes 443-506
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 8: Boxes 443-506
Kheel Center for Labor- Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 8: Boxes 443-506
6046
Kheel Center
388.2 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
The Archives Union File is a collection of publications of United States labor unions. Included is information on the American Institute for Free Labor Development. The AUF collection consists largely of pamphlets and publications of unions, collected by the Kheel Center.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into twelve sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-63
Section 2: Boxes 64-126
Section 3: Boxes 127-191
Section 4: Boxes 192-256
Section 5: Boxes 257-319
Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
Section 7: Boxes 379-442
Section 8: Boxes 443-506
Section 9: Boxes 507-571
Section 10: Boxes 572-635
Section 11: Boxes 636-699
Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this time.
SUBJECTS
Names:
AFL-CIO --Archives; AFL-CIO. American Institute for Free Labor Development--Archives; AFL-CIO. Building and Construction Trades Dept.--Archives; AFL-CIO. Department of Economic Research--Archives; AFL-CIO. Education Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Executive Council--Archives; AFL-CIO. Human Resources Development Institute--Archives; AFL-CIO. Industrial Union Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Legislative Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Public Employees Department--Archives; AFSCME --Archives; Air Line Pilots Association --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Research Department--Archives; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America --Archives; American Association of University Professors --Archives; American Federation of Government Employees --Archives; American Federation of Labor --Archives; American Federation of Musicians --Archives; American Federation of Teachers --Archives; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists --Archives; American Guild of Musical Artists --Archives; American Postal Workers Union --Archives; Association of Flight Attendants (U.S.) --Archives; Bakery, Confectionary and Tobacco Workers International Union --Archives; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.) --Archives; Communication Workers Union --Archives; Communications Workers of America --Archives; Congress of Industrial Organizations --Archives; Federation of Westinghouse Independent Salaried Unions --Archives; Hotel & Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union --Archives; Illinois State AFL-CIO --Archives; Industrial Workers of the World --Archives; International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers --Archives; International Association of Fire Fighters --Archives; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers --Archives; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades --Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Educational Department--Archives; International Longshoremens and Warehousemens Union --Archives; International Typographical Union --Archives; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; International Union of North American Laborers --Archives; International Union, Allied Industrial Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Ford Dept. --Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers --Archives; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) --Archives; National Association of Postal Supervisors --Archives; National Maritime Union of America --Archives; National Writers Union (U.S.) --Archives; New York State AFL-CIO --Archives; New York State United Teachers --Archives; Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union --Archives; Screen Actors Guild --Archives; Service Employees International Union --Archives; Sheet Metal Workers International Union --Archives; Teamsters for a Democratic Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America --Archives; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry --Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America --Archives; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; United Glass & Ceramic Workers of North America --Archives; United Mine Workers of America --Archives; United Office and Professionals Workers of America --Archives; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum and Plastic Workers of America --Archives; United Steelworkers of America --Archives; Utility Workers Union of America --Archives; Writer's Guild of America --Archives
Subjects:
Agricultural laborers--Labor unions; Airlines--Employees--Labor unions; Textile workers--Labor unions; Barbers--Labor unions; Building-service employees--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions; Construction workers--Labor unions; Automobile industry workers--Labor unions; Bakery employees--Labor unions; Transport workers--Labor unions; Fire fighters--Labor unions; Electricians--Labor unions; Plumbers--Labor unions; Teachers--Labor unions; Glassworkers--Labor unions; Restaurants--Employees--Labor unions; Postal service--Employees--Labor unions; Rubber industry and trade--Labor unions
Form and Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.; Publications
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this collection:
6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 2: Boxes 64-126
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 3: Boxes 127-191
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 4: Boxes 192-246
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 5: Boxes 257-319
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 7: Boxes 379-442
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 1: Boxes 1-63
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 9: Boxes 507-571
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 10: Boxes 572-635
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 11: Boxes 636-699
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this point.
Related Collections:
6046 mf: Archives Union File on Microfilm
CONTAINER LIST
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: What the Copper Strike is all about - 7th Constitutional Convention, 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations).
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Labor's views on Selective Service, 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Notes: Article.
  - Item 3: The Disaffiliation of the UAW, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Union members are everywhere, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Notes: Flyer.
  - Item 5: Fair housing exploding the myths, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: When great men agree, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: How to apply, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: You may be eligible, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: The hidden cost of not belonging, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Give youth a union hand up, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Truth in lending: what it means to you, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: The teen-wage fiction, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: The history of 14(b) and what it means, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Your library can help your union, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: 'Right to work' laws lower labor standards, 1965; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Notes: Revised edtion. Second copy
  - Item 16: Ten years of progress; a report on Israel, 1958; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Author: George M. Harrison; Jacob S. Potosky
    Notes: Submitted to George Meany and the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO, December 1, 1958. Second copy
  - Item 17: Safety in numbers, 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Notes: Article. 2 copies
  - Item 18: Working together ... the key to jobs for the handicapped: an AFL-CIO guide., 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Notes: Revised edition. 2 copies
  - Item 19: Labor looks at capitalism, 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Author: George Meany
    Notes: 2 copies
  - Item 20: Labor and equal rights, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
    Author: A. Philip Randolph
    Notes: This booklet contains the text of the Resolution on Civil Rights adopted by the Seventh AFL-CIO Convention at Bal Harbour, Fla., Dec. 7-12, 1967, and an address by AFL-CIO Vice President A. Philip Randolph, in support of the resolution.
  - Item 21: Catastrophic Insurance: blessing or disguise?, Publication (Box 443, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Adjusting to automation, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Author: Rudolph A. Oswald
    Notes: Second copy
  - Item 2: Is Collective Bargaining Dead?, 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Notes: Speech transcript
  - Item 3: State of Maryland v. W. Willard Wirtz (Civil Action 18005), 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Author: United States District Court of Maryland
  - Item 4: Unemployment Insurance under state laws, Jan 1, 1966, Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Figure it out yourself, 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Build economic understanding use an educational filmstrip to help teach economics, Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: correspondence: To Officers of State and City Central Bodies -- Senate debate on the confirmation of Clement F. Haynsworth as Associate Justice of the Supreme Court now is expected to start during the week of Nov. 10, 1969., Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: I'm out of a job, I'm all through, 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Notes: Article. Reprinted from Saturday Evening Post
  - Item 9: Correio Operario Norteamericano, 1966; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Notes: v.3:no.22
    Language: Spanish.
  - Item 10: How to balance the scales, 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Notes: Flyer
  - Item 11: Pay special attention to this month's LOM, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Union members split on Vietnam, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: Labor on Vietnam, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 14: Strike in Saigon is broken by Police, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
  - Item 15: The AFL-CIO platform proposals, 1968; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Notes: Presented to the Republican and Democratic national conventions.
  - Item 16: Bullets do not discriminate landlords do!, 1967; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
    Author: Lyndon B. Johnson
  - Item 17: Man and his environment, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Birth of the AFL-CIO, Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
    Notes: Booklet, labelled incomplete
  - Item 2: Cooperation...: the key to jobs for the handicapped, Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
    Notes: An AFL-CIO program for union-management action to probide employment for handicapped workers
  - Item 3: America honors labor, Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Union attitudes toward predetermined motion time systems, 1963; Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
    Author: Bertram Gottlieb
  - Item 5: Union security: the case against the compulsory open shop, 1960-1969 (Box 443, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Economic programs & policies for the 60's, 1961; Publication (Box 443, Folder 3)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Research Dept.
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Employer's stake in the open shop, Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: The consultants who coach the violators, Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
    Author: Phillis Payne
  - Item 3: 29 ideas for steward meetings, Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Convention call to the Twelfth Constitutional Convention, Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Statement by. On the Federal Reserve and the Nation's monetary policy, 1975; Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Executive Council.
  - Item 6: AFL-CIO News Service, 1975; Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
    Notes: Feb. 13, 19, 20, 24, 25 (1975)
  - Item 7: Text of resolution adopted at the eigth convention of the AFL-CIO in Atlantic City, NJ (Oct. 6&7, 1969), Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Films for young people on Labor and Social--Economic Issues, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Not for release until Tuesday, Nov. 18, 1969 -- Released by: Joseph Curran 11/14/69 -- New proposed Maritime Program, Publication (Box 443, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: article - Why Richard M. Nixon must be impeached -- now, 1973; Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: The labor movement in the United States, 1970; Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
    Author: John J. Flagler; Marc Rosenblum
    Notes: Traces the history of organized labor in the United States and discusses its influence on the society.
  - Item 3: The national economy 1977, Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: The national economy, 1975, Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: An action program to put America back to work, 1975; Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Equal rights for all-- the AFL-CIO program, 1970; Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
    Author: AFL- CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations).
  - Item 7: How to run a union meeting, 1972; Publication (Box 443, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The issue is tax justice: Coordinated Bargaining Committee, 1970; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Equal rights for all-- the AFL-CIO program, 1970; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Who is the imperialist?, 1951; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Author: AFL. Free Trade Union Committee
  - Item 4: International affairs resolutions, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Notes: Adopted October, 1969 by the Eighth Constitutional Convention American Federation of Labor, Congress of Industrial Organizations
  - Item 5: Policy resolutions on Urban Affairs and Housing, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Notes: Adopted October, 1969 by the Eighth Constitutional Convention American Federation of Labor, Congress of Industrial Organizations.
  - Item 6: We want tax justice!, 1960-1969 (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: How to run a union meeting, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: Statements adopted by the AFL-CIO Executive Council, New York, N.Y., August 6-8, 1969, Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Executive Council
  - Item 9: Rules governing AFL-CIO state central bodies, 1973; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: The Nixon Pay Board. A stacked deck., 1971; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Notes: Keynote address to the ninth AFL-CIO Convention, Bal Harbour, Fla., November 18, 1971. Second copy
  - Item 11: The national economy 1969, Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: A trade policy for America: an AFL-CIO Program (this pamphlet is based on testimony by AFL-CIO President George Meany), 1971; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Inflation with a profit twist, 1970; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: Toward eliminating poverty in America, 1969; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
  - Item 15: Energy: the AFL-CIO program., 1975; Publication (Box 443, Folder 6)
    Notes: This statement was adopted by the AFL-CIO Executive Council at its February 1975 meeting.
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Leaflet of the month -- [to be inserted in your organizaids binder from the AFL-CIO Dept of Organization, Publication (Box 444, Folder 1)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Dept. of Organization
  - Item 2: A program to build America's jobs and trade in the seventies, 1973; Publication (Box 444, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Resolution No. 25 -- Iowa organizing program, 1970; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Sept.-Nov. 1957 -- NLRB summary reports new records some good, some bad; Union s continue membership growth, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: July 1957 -- Miami area organizing gets results, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: June 1957 -- NLRB report shows effects of anti-union bias, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Dept. of Organization, 1964; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
    Notes: v.9:no.2 (1964:June)
  - Item 6: November 1959 -- Regional organizing confereces nearing completion; Anti-union campaighn continues, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Aug. 1957 -- NLRB reports great organizing activity; Baltimore campaign underway, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: May 1958 -- ABC campaign in high gear; NAM spearheads hate-union drive, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: April 1960 -- NLRB reports for 1959 show upturn in organizing activity by AFL-CIO affiliated unions; California agricultural drive begins second season, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Aug. 1960 -- Lines set for farm labor war, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: July 1961 -- NLRB seen returning to neutral role; General board to meet on organizing, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: President Meany says --We're with you and we are going to stay with you, 1968; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: Leaflet of the month -- [to be inserted in your organizaids binder from the AFL-CIO Dept of Organization, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 14: That's community without union, 1969; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 15: Some of my best friends are organizers but, Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Item 16: Number one objective, 1959; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). National Organizing Conference
    Notes: Report of the First AFL-CIO National Organizing Conference, January 6-7, 1959, Washington, D.C.
  - Item 17: Organizing that works: tips for union leaders, 1997; Publication (Box 444, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Political memo from COPE -- no. 1-26 -56, 1956; Publication (Box 444, Folder 3)
    Author: AFL- CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Committee on Political Education
  - Item 2: Political Action of the Week - no. 10, 1955; Publication (Box 444, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Cope facts no. 1 (Jan. 19, 1956), Publication (Box 444, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: Political Memo from COPE -- no. 1-26 -57, 1957; Publication (Box 444, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Platform proposals of the AFL-CIO to the Republican and Democratic National Conventions, 1964, Publication (Box 444, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE -- no. 1-28 -58, 1958; Publication (Box 444, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: 1958 handbook: background on issues, talking points, AFL-CIO policy, Publication (Box 444, Folder 6)
    Author: AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations). Committee on Political Education
  - Item 3: How to win; a handbook for political action, 1956; Publication (Box 444, Folder 6)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 444, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Collective bargaining report, 1957; Publication (Box 444, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Labor's economic review, 1957; Publication (Box 444, Folder 7)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE, 1959; Publication (Box 445, Folder 1)
    Notes: no.1-27 (1959)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE, 1960; Publication (Box 445, Folder 2)
    Notes: no. -26 (1960)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE, 1961; Publication (Box 445, Folder 3)
    Notes: no.1-26 (1961)
  - Item 2: Political Memo from COPE, 1962; Publication (Box 445, Folder 3)
    Notes: no.1-7, 9-27 (1962)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE, 1963; Publication (Box 445, Folder 4)
    Notes: no.1-13, 19-26 (1963)
  - Item 2: Political Memo from COPE, 1964; Publication (Box 445, Folder 4)
    Notes: no.1-9, 11-19, 21-26 (1964)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Political Memo from COPE, 1965; Publication (Box 445, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.1, 3-26 (1965)
  - Item 2: Political Memo from COPE, 1966; Publication (Box 445, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.1-7 (196)6
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Speakers' handbook, 1964; Publication (Box 445, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Speakers' handbook, 1966; Publication (Box 445, Folder 6)
- AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations)., Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Recession hits both farmer and worker, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: America must have, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Boy did I get hooked!, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: A pocketbook of politics, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: What an extra dollar or two can do, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: They gave... and how!, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: You can't vote, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Do you have COPE insurance?, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: ow close can you get?, Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)
  - Item 10: Your COPE dollar..., Publication (Box 445, Folder 7)